(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING)
(GUNSHOT)
-(WARCRIES ON TV)
-(GUNSHOTS)
(BELL DINGS)
(MAN)
The kid's a fucking weirdo.
He's always saying weird shit.
(WOMAN) Jesus, Dillon.
He's just a kid!
He's got a big imagination.
(DILLON) I mean, why is he even
living here anyway?
(WOMAN)
Because he's my little brother
and he doesn't have
anywhere else to go.
(DILLON) So I have to be the one
to keep a roof over his head?
(WOMAN) Oh, poor you.
I'm sure the overhead
of this grand estate...
(DILLON) Jesus fuck, Mandy.
(MANDY) ...is such
a terrible fucking burden.
Asshole.
(MAN ON TV) If you ain't
outta this town in 24 hours,
you'll be carried out.
What the fuck you wearing?
Ceremonial headband.
Why are you wearing
a ceremonial headband?
I'm the reincarnation
of Sitting Bull,
the great Lakota war chief.
I've returned to your world
to lead my band of warriors
into battle once again.
Man, cut that shit out.
It's offensive.
(TALKING ON TV CONTINUES)
(CHILD ON TV) He hates me.
He hates all of us.
Just because we're Indians.
Why? What's wrong with us?
Are we evil?
(GUNSHOT)
(WOMAN ON TV)
What are you going to do?
(MAN ON TV)
I'm still an Indian.
Like my father before me,
my son is my honor.
I go now to my enemy's house
to hurl the arrow of war
at his feet.
(UPBEAT BANJO STRUMMING)
I did it. I fucking did it!
Okay. Grab your shit.
I got his keys. I got his cell.
We gotta go.
You listening to me?
-(CAR DOOR SLAMS)
-Hey, listen. We gotta scram
before somebody
calls in the Sheriff.
Listen to me.
I just smashed that son
of a bitch's head in. All right?
Let's go!
I can't go.
My people need me.
I am your people, numb nuts.
Come on.
Calvin, listen to me.
This isn't one of
your cowboy movies, Calvin.
This is real life.
Get in the car.
-(GASPING)
-(METAL CLANKS)
Hey. Hey!
Jesus. Okay, I hear you.
Put that down.
Fuck.
(WIND WHISTLES)
Calvin, I am begging you.
Please do not make me
leave you here.
Get in the car!
I am the reincarnation
of Sitting Bull.
-Yeah, I know what you are--
-(DILLON GROANS)
But we still have to
get out of here.
Listen, I'm going home.
Home, home.
Real home. Okay?
Go to the Whitley's house.
Stay there with them.
They'll take care of you.
Probably better than I can,
honestly.
I have a plan.
If everything goes the way
it's supposed to,
I'm gonna get us out of here.
For real. I promise.
My home is here
in the Great Spirit.
What the fuck
am I supposed to say to that?
(ENGINE STARTS)
Go to the Whitley's house.
-(MAN) Fuck!
-(GASPS)
God damn it! Fuck!
(INHALES, GROANS)
(SIGHS)
Oh, that bitch. (SIGHS)
(YAWNS)
Where is she?
Did she take my fucking car?
Fucking hell. Hey, knock it off.
You little shit!
Motherfucker.
Hey, shit for brains.
I said knock it off.
(GUNSHOTS)
God damn it. Are you going to
make me come over there
and shoot your ass?
(MUFFLED GRUNT)
(INHALES SLOWLY)
(SLOWLY) Yeah.
(YELLING WAR CRY)
(WIND WHISTLING)
("I'LL BE HERE IN THE MORNING"
BY TOWNES VAN ZANDT PLAYING)
♪ There's no stronger wind
Than the one that blows ♪
♪ Down
A lonesome railroad line ♪
♪ No prettier sight
Than looking back ♪
♪ On a town you left behind ♪
♪ But there's nothing
That's as real ♪
♪ As a love that's in my mind ♪
♪ Close your eyes
I'll be here in the morning ♪
♪ Close your eyes... ♪
(DISHES CLATTERING)
I know my life isn't exciting.
I know I'm not too exciting
either.
I don't have a fancy job.
I don't drive a fancy car.
I'm not a part of
any kind of country club.
But I have a nice house,
a strong back...
and a heart full of love
to give.
(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING QUIETLY)
The world is so full
of bad things, it's...
It's frightening.
Especially if you're alone.
No one should be alone.
People, they...
People ought to... Oh.
Oh, gosh. Happy... happy...
People should be happy.
(CHUCKLES)
I think I can make you happy.
And that's why I want you
to be my happy wife
and for me to be
your happy husband.
Brittany Gable.
Will you marry me? (EXHALES)
How was it?
Wha-- What do you think?
(STAMMERING)
I... think it sounds... nice.
You think I should ask her
today?
W-Well, it's not really...
for me to say.
-Well, sure it is.
-(COFFEE CUP CLINKS)
Uh... I'm-- I'm just a waitress.
I-I-I don't-- I don't...
really know you. (SIGHS)
Oh. Lefty Ledbetter.
Sure, you do.
I come in here every day.
You know how I like my eggs.
-(BELL DINGS)
-Order up.
How I like my coffee.
My girlfriend
doesn't even know that.
How long have you... two...
been together?
(CLICKS TONGUE)
About two weeks.
We're having lunch today.
I was thinking of asking her
to marry me after dessert.
-Order up.
-(BELL DINGS)
Well, I-I hope it... goes well.
(NERVOUS CHUCKLE)
Hmm.
M-Maybe you should...
work a little... more
on memorizing your... speech,
so you don't have to use
the index cards.
Good idea.
-(EXHALES)
-Good thinking.
I... I'm sorry.
Yeah.
I know my life isn't exciting.
("CATTLE CALL"
BY TEX OWENS PLAYING)
(LEFTY CONTINUES) I know
I'm not too exciting either.
I don't have a fancy job.
I don't drive a fancy car.
I'm not a member
of any kind of country club.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(SIGHS)
But I have a nice house,
a strong back, and
a heart full of love to give.
The world is so full
of bad things.
-(CHUCKLES)
-It's frightening.
Especially if you're alone.
No one should be alone.
-People should be happy.
-(CAR STARTS)
I think I can make you happy.
That's why I want you
to be my happy wife
and for me to be
your happy husband.
-(CAR ENGINE HUMMING)
-(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Brittany Gable.
Will you marry me?
(BELL DINGS)
Lefty,
this is, like, our third date.
-Uh, fourth.
-(BELL DINGS)
But we also had lunch
last Tuesday.
Don't you love me?
Hi, Brittany.
-Robert. Diana. Good afternoon.
-Hi.
-Congratulations.
-Oh.
-Don't you?
-No.
I mean, you're cute
and you're nice,
but I don't really even
know you yet.
(SIGHS)
Hey, I'm sorry.
Um, let me take you home.
I'll get your bag.
No, that's okay.
I can call a friend.
No, you don't...
Hey, Brittany. Please.
Just how often do you do this?
-Not that often.
-(BELL DINGS)
How many times this year?
-Counting you?
-Yes, counting me.
How many women have you asked
to marry you this year?
Three.
Wait. Sorry.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
That's four just now.
I don't think we should
see each other again.
Hey, Debbie, it's me.
Can I ask you a favor?
(SIGHS)
Yeah, that is four.
("COUNTRY GIRL"
BY GONE WEST PLAYING)
Warm up?
Thank you.
Hey, uh, has he seen me?
(MAN ON PHONE) Write this down.
I don't want you
to screw this up.
(WAITRESS, STAMMERING)
No, I-I don't think so.
(MAN CHATTERING)
Real money.
Thank God.
Son of a bitch would rat me out.
I don't have permission to
be out of the house right now.
-I think he's... leaving.
-All right.
-Mm-hmm.
-One sec.
Uh, he's-- he's leaving.
You can take the...
door out back
through the...
kitchen if you want.
You're real sweet. Thank you.
("COUNTRY GIRL"
CONTINUES PLAYING)
-(COOK) Order here.
-(BELL DINGS)
("BOULDER TO BIRMINGHAM"
BY EMMYLOU HARRIS PLAYING)
♪ I don't want to
Hear a love song ♪
♪ I got on this airplane
Just to fly ♪
♪ And I know there's life
Below me ♪
♪ But all that you can show me
Is the prairie and the sky ♪
-(MUSIC STOPS)
-(ENGINES REV)
("HIER IN DER WIRKLICHKEIT"
BY DIRK MAVERICK PLAYING)
Hello, darlin'.
Are you a member or guest?
Let's say she's my guest, Wim.
Yeah.
Can we get two beers on my tab?
(CHUCKLES)
If that's okay with you.
(STAMMERING)
Sure... It is.
Yeah?
All right, then.
-How'd the... proposal go?
-Not great.
("WALK THROUGH THIS WORLD WITH
ME" BY GEORGE JONES PLAYING)
(GRUNTS)
W-W-Wait.
Shouldn't you...
u-use your other... hand?
Why?
Well, your... name.
Lefty. Yeah, it's my birth name.
Lefty Gabriel Ledbetter.
It's on my birth certificate.
But you're right... handed?
Uh-huh. Always have been.
(DART CLATTERS)
(SIGHS) Yeah.
It's poor equilibrium.
You... don't seem drunk.
I'm not. Brain injury.
I was driving transport
outside Kabul.
I hit an IED. 0300 hours.
Here.
Go on, you can feel the scar.
I don't mind.
Oh. Okay, I... guess.
That's a... big scar.
Yeah, it's noticeable.
They had to split my head open
to get inside.
I consider myself lucky,
you know.
They didn't find anything.
("RAINY DAY BLUES"
BY WILLIE NELSON PLAYING)
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, that's a joke.
(LAUGHS)
You have a nice laugh.
Thank you.
I like your voice, too.
N-N-No, you don't. No one
wants to hear my... s-stammer.
Well, I like it.
Or I don't mind it, at least.
If you didn't speak that way,
I don't think
you'd give me the time of day.
At... least you're honest.
I have to be honest.
I've never been much of a...
I've never been much
of a deep thinker.
Even before the accident.
Old Wim says he can't
even tell the difference.
Deep thinking's overrated.
I think... d-deep shit
all the time and...
look where it's gotten me.
You just swore.
You said a curse word.
I'm off the... clock.
I can say
whatever the... fuck I want.
-(BOTH CHUCKLE)
-(LEFTY COUGHS)
Well, all right then.
May I buy you another round?
Yes, you... may.
All right.
Hey, Wim. How about two more?
-(STRUMS)
-(CHUCKLES)
-(HUMMING)
-(STRUMMING)
Well,
look what the cat dragged in.
Do you have any idea
what time it is?
(STAMMERING)
I w-was... trying to be quiet.
(MOCKING)
I-I-I don't wanna h-h-hear it.
I'm trying to s-sleep.
I-- I'm...
sorry.
Then get your sorry ass in bed.
Some of us gotta work
in the morning.
One more day until the weekend,
Frenchie.
They say it might rain.
Of course, they say
a lot of things, don't they?
-(HORSE SNORTS)
-Hey, I got you.
Penny Jo?
(CHUCKLES)
I-I thought these... could use
a little-- little more sunlight.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Well, hi-- hi there.
Hello.
Do you have a m-minute?
Sure, I do. Yes.
Okay, good. 'Cause, um...
I've got a... really dumb idea
I'd like to... run by you.
Sure. Uh, let's...
I think...
something's gonna... go down
at the diner at 4:00 today.
You're late.
Actually, I'm not. 3:59.
(MUSIC PLAYS, FAINT)
We should have done this
in private.
Sorry, pal.
You think I'm stupid enough to
meet you in a private location?
Have we ordered yet?
No, we're waiting for you.
Which doesn't mean I'm late.
(MAN CLEARS THROAT)
Can I get you fellas
something to eat?
I guess I'll take a BLT
with fries and a Coke.
(STAMMERING)
And, um... how about you... two?
Maybe you should come back
in a minute.
I think they're having...
a staring contest.
I'll have a cheeseburger,
well done, side of fries
and whatever's good on tap.
And you?
Oh, are we eating?
I guess I'm not late after all.
(CLEARS THROAT) Look,
if you wanna turn this into
some kind of Pat Garrett and
Billy the Kid type situation,
please do so,
'cause I've been wanting
to do that
pretty much
my entire fucking life.
Hmm?
I'll have a Cobb salad with
balsamic vinaigrette on the side
and just an ice water to drink.
I'm trying to watch
my girlish figure.
(CHUCKLES)
And how about you, hon?
Um, I'll have the Cobb salad
with balsamic vinaigrette
on the side.
Perfect.
Okay, so... there's
this artifact I got my eye on.
Now it's nothing too flashy...
What is it?
I was getting to that. Jesus.
It's an old Indian shirt that's
fallen onto the black market.
And like I said, it's nothing
too flashy, but all things even,
I would prefer it to be
in the hands
of someone such as myself
who could actually
appreciate it.
Right now,
it's in a private collection
and the owner claims
it's not for sale.
But if someone were to
make an effort
to liberate that garment,
I would pay...
...six grand. Flat rate.
Straight cash. One time offer.
Why do you want it?
Why would you think you're
in any position to ask that?
Okay. Fair enough.
May I gently inquire
as to how much it's worth?
It's worth enough to pay you
six grand to bring it to me,
but not so much I can't pay
any other local thug if pushed.
Okay.
Ten grand.
Dillon, come on.
He wants pros,
he can pay pro rates.
Ten.
You better be as good
as Kip Blanchard says you are.
(DILLON) Buddy, I'm better.
All right. Ten it is.
Congratulations.
Be right back. Oh... sorry.
Thank you, sweetheart.
Okay, the current owner's name
is Pendleton Duvall.
He likes to
spend his weekends hosting
high culture dinner parties
deep into the night.
So, guests but no alarm.
Think you can handle that?
Take a wild guess.
-(CELL PHONE VIBRATES)
-Excuse me.
Shit, I gotta get this.
Give me one second, gentlemen.
-Hello?
-(CLEARS THROAT)
Yeah. Hey. What's up, amigo?
(GROANS)
(WHISTLING)
(MAN) Order here.
Sorry, Hank.
-Order up.
-(BELL DINGS)
Hey. Good timing, hombre.
Uh-huh.
Yeah. Well, um...
I should have the ghost shirt...
I don't know,
after this weekend.
Yeah.
Well, but, you know,
if you're gonna want me
to hold you in first position,
I'm gonna need
some type of guarantee.
Gotta be honest with you,
you're not the only
interested party here.
And with the ghost shirt
being what it is
and me being who I am...
you're gonna need to present me
with a nice, juicy number
right about fucking now.
I'm thinking
half a million dollars
sounds like a fucking peach.
Uh-huh.
Congratulations, my friend.
You are currently
in first position.
I'll let you know when and where
to make the exchange.
(STAMMERING) Half a...
million dollars. Really?
That's what the man said.
So, I... guess that's... that.
They aren't just... gonna
give us the artifact, you know.
(SIGHS)
What are you gonna do
with the m-m-money
when we get it?
You know, I don't really
need it. (CHUCKLES)
You should--
You should keep it.
Oh, you...
don't have to do that.
I already got everything I need,
really.
Good food, good beer.
Uh, good company, you know.
I... bet they have all that
in... Nashville.
-Nash-- Nashville?
-Mm-hmm.
Once we get the... artifact,
I'm gonna... sell it
for the... big bucks
and go there to...
sing professionally.
Sing profe--
I didn't know you were a singer.
Nobody does.
-I'm a hidden... gem.
-Wow.
-What kinda songs do you sing?
-Mmm.
Cheating songs. Drinking songs.
Hurting songs.
You sing country music?
What other kinda...
music is there?
Yup.
Wow.
Could you sing
one of your songs for me?
Uh... n-n-no.
I-I-I'd be-- be too nervous
to sing in front of you.
Well, then how are you
gonna sing professionally?
W-We'll cross that... bridge
when we get there.
("TAKE SOME LOVE"
BY JOHNNY LIDELL PLAYING)
Do you, uh... Do you write
any of your own songs?
Um... Mm-hmm.
-About... 43 of them.
-Forty--
-That's a whole lot.
-(LAUGHS)
Yeah, but I-I... think only
about four of them are any good.
Mmm.
I also kn-know all the songs
of m-my heroes.
Yeah. Who are they?
Dolly... Parton.
Loretta Lynn.
Tanya... Tucker.
Tammy... Wynette.
Dolly... Parton. Emmylou...
You said Dolly Parton twice.
-God... damn right I... did.
-(CHUCKLES)
I don't know
how anybody could...
live in this...
world without music.
(LEFTY)
Hey, you know, I've...
I've heard that
Nashville's a real nice city.
("'TIL I CAN MAKE IT ON MY OWN"
BY TAMMY WYNETTE PLAYS)
♪ I'll need time ♪
Do you know
how to... two-step?
(SCOFFS)
No. No, I'm afraid I don't.
How about you?
Not really. (CHUCKLES)
But if we're going to...
Nashville, we'd... better learn.
(CHUCKLES)
How do you-- How do you expect
we do that?
♪ 'Til I get used to
Losing you ♪
Yeah. Come on.
♪ Let me keep on using you ♪
(CLEARS THROAT)
How do... Oh.
Go like... (MUTTERS)
♪ I'll get by ♪
One step.
(SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY)
♪ But no matter how I try ♪
(PENNY JO GIGGLES)
♪ There'll be times
You know I'll call ♪
-(LEFTY SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
-(GIGGLES)
(MUSIC FADES)
(MAN) After every bad election
or bit of mass violence,
you will always hear someone
clutch their pearls and say,
"That's it,
I'm moving to Canada."
And they should go back
to Canada
because it's a mecca
for pedants and bores.
But it does beg the question,
why does America, with
all this violence and toxicity
and problematic history,
produce more artistic geniuses
than any other fucking country?
Well, maybe it's not that
they create...
Thanks, Mumbles.
I'll tell you why.
Okay.
It's because
what Americans imagine
takes precedence
over what is real.
Hmm? We reside in the possible.
The possible is our birthright.
We are born into the possible.
Look. Take the newest addition
to my humble
little collection here.
("WALK ME TO THE SHORE"
BY HOT DAMN SCANDAL PLAYS)
A Lakota Indian ghost shirt.
Hello? A fucking ghost shirt.
Crickets? The fuck?
(STAMMERS AND SIGHS)
-Okay. Okay. Okay.
-(LOW ENGINE RUMBLE)
Once upon a time,
the Lakota Indian controlled
all of this land that
we are currently on right now.
I mean,
every fucking inch of it.
Until one day that one little
raggedy prospector finds gold
in them thar black hills
and, well, long story short,
things turn a bit genocidal.
So, the Lakota lose
the rest of their land.
All their bison is gone.
They lose their independence.
The government tears up
all their fucking treaties
because of the gold,
and the Lakota are left
with fucking nothing.
I mean, they are bereft, yo.
In that vacuum,
a new religion starts to spread
through Indian territory.
It takes hold.
It's a religion
based on one simple idea.
That Jesus Christ--
Oh, he's a little pissed off,
and he's coming back.
But the Lakota...
They didn't just think that
Jesus Christ was coming back.
No, they thought that
Jesus Christ was coming back
on a mission to remove
the white man
from this, their sacred land.
And what would keep them safe
during this war to end all wars?
Yeah. The ghost shirt.
-Hmm.
-(SCOFFS)
Excuse me.
This is fascinating, Pendleton.
(DILLON) Hold up.
(WOMAN)
Didn't they think these shirts
would stop
the white man's bullets?
(PENDLETON)
Yes, indeed they did.
And for the Lakota, believing
that they were invincible
was, of course,
the next best thing
-to actually being invincible.
-(WOMAN SCOFFS)
So feel free to look closer.
You should see this
in the morning.
Hmm.
("CELLO SUITE NO 1 IN G MAJOR"
BY ALEXANDER RUDIN PLAYS)
(PENDLETON) With the sunlight.
(CONTINUES INDISTINCTLY)
(MAN)
I'm guessing we should go?
-(SILENCED GUNSHOTS)
-Oh!
Oh, shit.
Hey! Slow down.
Oh, hey, hey, hey. Hey.
I'm going to assume that you
possess the capacity to reason.
As it stands,
I have a great deal of money.
Therefore... Therefore,
I propose we talk. Hmm?
(WOMAN SOBBING)
(GROANS, GRUNTS)
(GROANING)
(WOMAN SHRIEKING)
He's right.
It's just a fucking shirt.
(GROANING)
-(WOMAN) Don't shoot!
-(TWO SILENCED GUNSHOTS)
(THUD)
(GRUNTS, PANTING)
Wait. How much
are they paying you?
200,000? 300. I can top that.
-Ten grand.
-(PANTING)
Split two ways.
-Ten grand?
-(CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHING) Fucking Jesus.
You fucking...
I regret to inform you,
my bandit friend...
that you are being screwed.
A big, veiny cock in your ass.
(PANTING)
That bitch was nimble, man.
So that's it, huh?
Nice.
Dude.
You weren't planning on walking
around with the murder weapon?
Go start the car.
Yo, D. See her?
(Dillon) Start the car.
(EXHALES)
Hey.
Just how much
is that fucking thing worth?
Yeah. Whose ass
is getting fucked now?
("CELLO SUITE NO 1 IN G MAJOR"
BY ALEXANDER RUDIN CONTINUES)
-(ENGINE HUMMING)
-(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(EXHALES)
(ENGINE ROARS)
When you gotta go, you gotta go.
Give me a sec, okay?
Probably just something I ate.
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(SOBBING)
(CRYING QUIETLY)
Fuck. (PANTING)
First we kill a house
full of innocent people.
Now we're driving around
with a goddamn Indian
burial ground in the trunk.
This is bad, man.
This is so bad.
-(GRUNTING)
-(SHOUTING)
(EXHALES)
Fucking hell.
(WIND WHISTLING)
-(PHONE RINGS)
-(PHONE VIBRATES)
Hey.
Pack your shit.
We're leaving the state.
Pack my shit. Why?
I'm like, three,
maybe just four hours away.
I'll tell you more
when I get there.
But let's just say your life's
gonna be all rose petals
and scented candles
from this day forward.
I hate scented candles.
(SIGHS) Then no candles.
Jesus. Fuck, Mandy.
Just shut your hole
and get to packing, okay?
(UPBEAT BANJO STRUMMING)
(LEFTY) Huh.
(SIGHS)
(INDISTINCT VOICES
ON TELEVISION)
(MAN ON TV)
Let's get outta here!
(SHOUTING)
(SNIFFLES)
(INDISTINCT TV CHATTER
CONTINUES)
(GUNFIRE ON TV)
(CAR ENGINE RUMBLING)
You packed?
For what?
Of course. Absolutely. For what?
You like Indian shit, right?
Check it out.
Weird little fucking brother.
What the fuck, Mandy?
I told you
we had to leave the state.
(GROANS) You leave the state.
I'm going back to sleep.
God damn it!
I got, like, a million-dollar
artifact in the trunk of my car.
Mm-hmm.
Mandy, we gotta leave,
like, right fucking now.
(WHINING) No, I'm tired.
Fuck.
Sometimes I wish I was queer.
You know that?
Then I wouldn't have to put up
with a dumb fucking broad
just to get my nut off.
I mean, what is it exactly?
Biology?
Psychology?
Does just having a fetid
fucking gash between your legs
automatically render you
incapable of rational thought?
-(MANDY GRUNTS)
-(GROANS)
(THUD)
I have a plan.
If everything goes the way
it's supposed to,
I'm gonna get us out of here.
For real. I promise.
My home is here
in the Great Spirit.
(PENNY JO)
I think I know who... that is.
She took my fucking car.
Fucking hell.
Hey, knock it off.
God damn it.
Are you gonna make me come
over there and shoot your ass?
(BIRD TWEETS)
I am the reincarnation
of Sitting Bull,
the great Lakota war chief.
("CIRCLES" BY DREZUS
AND DAKOTA BEAR PLAYS)
♪ I love me some commas
But love my community more ♪
♪ Grew me some braids ♪
♪ Beat me some odds ♪
♪ But trust me
It left me with so many scars ♪
♪ I'm painting a picture ♪
♪ He tell me to get it
I'm with it, I'm gone ♪
♪ Like, what is you on? ♪
♪ Been grinding so long ♪
♪ I'm never no stingy ♪
♪ The Afghan is blowin' ♪
♪ I'm back in the city
Like, whoa ♪
♪ I play with the pivot ♪
♪ No changing my image ♪
♪ We more than
Just arrows and bows ♪
♪ I come from the bottom
I'm still at the bottom ♪
♪ But baby
I'm dipping my toes ♪
♪ No longer whipping
And flipping them Os ♪
♪ Mama's so proud
Cuz mama she know ♪
♪ I do this
For babies who brown ♪
♪ Someone go give them
They crowns ♪
♪ Give them they flowers... ♪
Not much time for chitchat, kid.
Talk.
I am the reincarnation
of Sitting Bull,
the great Lakota war chief.
(CHUCKLES) It sounds like
somebody's been watching
too many
cowboy and Indian movies.
I have traveled
through centuries of death,
only to discover that
you have abandoned the customs,
the culture,
the weapons of our people.
Way too many.
Yo, Hank.
What the fuck, man?
Found him snooping around.
Kid says he's Sitting Bull.
You believe that? Sitting Bull.
Okay. Weird white kid. Noted.
That weird white kid
lives in the same trailer
as Dillon MacIntosh.
You heard. The ghost shirt
was stolen last night.
Yeah. Some thugs took out
a house full of bougie cunts.
Good riddance, motherfucker.
Shit.
Well, word is Big Fun Dave
was found stabbed
to death this morning.
Some empty quarry
halfway between there and here.
And you think
those two stole the shirt?
I did see him
at the diner the other day
talking with Roy Lee Dean.
That colonialist, black market
artifact stealing motherfucker.
Roy Lee Dean.
Stolen ghost shirt.
Big Fun Dave murdered.
Now baby Billy Jack's wandering
around the rez.
-Huh.
-Maybe he knows something.
Yeah.
Men make their own history,
but they do not make it
as they please.
Franz Fanon, right?
Or is it that Zizek guy
you like so much?
Dude, you gotta do your reading.
That is Karl motherfucking Marx.
Now come on.
Let's see if the little shit
knows some shit.
(DOOR CREAKS, SHUTS)
Okay, kid.
We know you live
with Dillon MacIntosh.
What's he been up to?
You're into Indians, right?
Well, you got
the real motherfucking deal
right here in front of you.
He's Hank. I'm Ghost Eye.
Let's talk.
Ghost Eye.
Is that your spirit name?
No.
Were you given it
after a special deed or vision?
No, I made it up.
You what?
Look,
my birth name's Alvin Jordan.
Ghost Dog's,
like, my favorite movie
and Ghostface Killah's up there
in terms of rappers, so...
Ghost Dog?
Yeah. With Forest Whitaker.
It's about a black
gangbanger assassin dude
who's actually a samurai.
RZA did the soundtrack.
Old Gary Farmer's
got a cool cameo.
You should check it out.
It's great.
Ah, shit. Let me guess.
You got questions
about tepees and peace pipes.
Shit like that?
I can speak with you, Hank.
You still seem to know
the old ways.
Hey. You pull
this red-faced minstrel shit
on the wrong guy out here,
you're gonna end up
with a tactical tomahawk
in the middle of your forehead.
So be it.
This vessel
can be discarded for another.
can be discarded for another?
What the fuck is that? Huh?
Is that how you think we talk?
It does not take much words
to speak the truth.
Many. The quote is,
"It does not take many words,"
and actually, sometimes it does.
So, have you seen Dillon today
or what?
Yes, I have.
Yeah? Good.
Did he happen to have
an old Indian shirt with him?
Yes.
No shit.
Is it still at your house?
No. The white woman has it.
What white woman?
Your mom, your sister, who?
My family resides
in the Great Spirit.
They are free
of this wretched earth.
Come on, kid. Holy shit.
Look, I get it.
My childhood
was a shit show, too.
I used to pretend
I was Jimmy Superfly Snuka
until I was, like, 13 years old.
So the trauma, the transference,
I get that.
But you gotta cut
this motherfucking shit out.
This ain't exactly
the golden age
of cultural appropriation
right now.
You feel me?
I remember more horses
in my day.
Motherfucker.
(SCOFFS, CHUCKLES)
Ah, it's just as well. Hmm?
All this modern technology
and political red tape.
Shit, I bet you Sitting Bull
wouldn't even be able
to lead his people
to the ghost shirt
these days anyway.
Of course he would.
Oh, yeah? So where is it?
The white woman said
she was returning to
her father's house in Wyoming.
In her words, a man
of great cruelty and violence.
I assume the ghost shirt
is with her.
("ANYTHING COULD HAPPEN"
BY THE CLEAN PLAYING)
-(CELL PHONE RINGS)
-(MACHINE BEEPS)
Hi, Daddy. It's me, Amanda.
Um... look,
I really need your help,
so if you promise
not to shoot me on sight, I...
I think I'm gonna come home.
♪ Went to a doctor
Said I look so hard ♪
♪ And with a smile on his face
But him into a junkyard ♪
♪ Look for an answer
In empty doorways ♪
♪ Talk to a dancer
Said it's out on the highway ♪
(LEFTY) Same plan?
(PENNY JO) Same... plan.
♪ I'm feeling cold boy
Feeling hot ♪
♪ Doctor said no, boy
You gotta learn ♪
♪ First don't shoot up
And then it's your turn ♪
♪ Well, anything could happen
And it could be right now ♪
(HANK) All right. Tie his hands.
(BOY GRUNTING)
(WHIMPERS)
Okay, Sitting Bull.
("ANYTHING COULD HAPPEN"
BY THE CLEAN CONTINUES)
♪ Make the cancellation
And I got numb ♪
♪ I haven't the motivation
To get myself... ♪
-(ENGINE STOPS)
-(MUSIC STOPS)
(BEEPING)
(BEEPS)
(SIGHS)
Beautiful day today.
Still, they say it might rain.
Yup.
Any big weekend plans?
Hey, buddy,
today is not the fucking day.
I'm really...
(STAMMERING)
Do you have the artifact?
I thought you were sweet.
(STAMMERS) Do you have it?
Maybe.
G-Give it to me.
(BELL DINGS)
No.
G-G-Give me the arti--
(CHUCKLES)
(NOZZLE CLANKS)
Do it. Just give it to me.
Fuck you. Shoot me.
(PERCUSSIVE
COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING)
(ENGINE REVS)
(UPBEAT COUNTRY MUSIC)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(ENGINE REVS)
(GRUNTS)
(PENNY JO)
She's... getting away.
-(TIRES SCREECHING)
-(PRIUS HORN HONKING)
(PENNY JO)
Where the... fuck did she go?
(ENGINE RATTLING)
("WONDROUS LOVE" BY JEAN RITCHIE
AND THE REVELS CHORUS PLAYS)
♪ What wondrous love is this? ♪
♪ Oh, my soul ♪
♪ What wondrous love is this ♪
♪ That calls
The Lord of bliss ♪
♪ To send this perfect peace ♪
♪ To my soul ♪
You know, driving up here,
I was a little afraid the boys
wouldn't know who I was.
But I suppose
they can still recognize
my traditional feminine virtues
after all these years.
I see you still haven't lost
your sense of humor.
(BIRDS TWEETING)
Okay.
All right.
You win.
You were right and I was wrong.
Father knows best.
The world is corrupt,
and I never should've left.
All of it.
Hello, Amanda.
Your mother and sisters
are inside.
House rules still apply.
You're welcome to enter
if you're willing to abide them.
Thank you, sir.
(LEFTY SIGHS)
She must've went down there.
(PENNY JO SIGHS)
All right.
I had, um... look...
There were children.
You did the right thing.
(SIGHS)
You stay here.
(STAMMERING)
Where-- where are you going?
You should wait in the truck.
Keep your gun close.
No, I-I-I don't...
think we should... do this.
That artifact is worth
a lot of money.
I know, but...
Well, you need the money
to go to Nashville.
You need to show the world
what you can do.
Yeah, but... there's other...
ways, but I--
I can... get a second j-job.
I-I-- I could...
Are you any good?
At... singing?
I-I-I don't kn-know.
Yes, you do.
Yeah.
I'm... pretty... fucking good.
There you go.
(LIGHT KNOCKING)
(WHISPERS)
I can't believe you came back.
Yeah, well,
it's just for tonight.
Then I'll get my ass
out of here again.
So, where you been
all these years?
Oklahoma.
New Jersey.
South Dakota.
Paradise.
So...
if you're gonna leave again...
are you gonna take us
with you this time?
Abby, I can't even
take care of myself.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATES)
I'm sorry.
Don't forget
to wash off your makeup.
House rules.
You know how Father gets.
(VIBRATING CONTINUES)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(DEAN) You have
the ghost shirt, right?
Is he dead?
Dillon? (SCOFFS)
Yeah, he's pretty fucking dead.
Shit. Look,
I didn't mean to kill him.
Look, lady,
I don't give a shit, all right?
As a matter of fact,
I don't give a shit who you are
or why you did it.
All I want is the artifact,
and I'm willing to pay a very
generous amount of money for it.
How generous?
(SIGHS)
$100,000 in cash. Final offer.
Fuck. Okay. How do we do it?
How do you think we do it?
I give you the money,
you give me the shirt.
-Has it been damaged?
-I don't think so.
You alone?
Yeah.
Should I pin
my location for you?
What an inspired idea.
Yeah, that'd be great.
Okay, you should be
getting it right now.
Are you going to be calling
from this number,
-or should I expect...
-(BEEPING)
(SCOFFS)
("SOME SAY" BY MELANIE PLAYING)
♪ Some say I got devil ♪
♪ Some say I got angel ♪
♪ But I'm just
A girl in trouble ♪
♪ I don't think I'm in danger
Don't think I'm in danger ♪
♪ No, I know
I'm not in danger ♪
♪ But some have tried
To sell me ♪
♪ All kinds of things
To save me ♪
♪ From hurting like a woman
And crying like a baby ♪
♪ Something like a woman ♪
♪ Crying like a baby ♪
♪ And all the things
That I have seen ♪
♪ Qualify me for ♪
♪ A part in your dream ♪
♪ Qualify me for... ♪
♪ And though
I'd like to tell it ♪
♪ Exactly how I feel it ♪
♪ Somehow the music
Hides it and conceals it ♪
♪ Hides it and conceals it ♪
♪ Oh, it hides... ♪
♪ And all the things ♪
♪ That I have seen ♪
♪ Can be hidden in ♪
♪ A part of my dream ♪
♪ Gonna hide it in my dream ♪
♪ Some say I've got devil ♪
♪ Some say I got angel ♪
♪ But I'm just
This girl in trouble ♪
♪ I don't think I'm in danger ♪
♪ No, I'm not in danger ♪
♪ No, I know
I'm not in danger ♪
Hey. W-What the heck are you...
doing all the way out here?
(HANK) Stay down. Stay quiet.
Trust me on this.
(GHOST EYE) And now,
we have two chits to trade.
(CALVIN MURMURS)
Hi, Mom.
I missed you.
(WHISPERS) Where's Calliope?
How you feeling, son?
I'm fine.
I'm just... I'm fine.
You are a guest
in an unfamiliar home
with unfamiliar customs.
A certain discomfort
is understandable.
Yeah, sure. I guess that's it.
At first.
Though, eventually a host
can't help but take offense
if that discomfort
doesn't eventually subside.
Oh. I'm sorry, sir.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Amanda?
Yes, sir.
Please help our guest relax.
Thank you.
Adam was formed first, then Eve.
But it was Eve, not Adam,
who was first led into sin.
So, it follows
that Eve's role now
is to support Adam.
To please and comfort him.
(DOOR OPENS)
In reparation.
Hiram, sir, we found some joker
snooping around the woods.
(DOOR OPENS)
So... what are you?
Federal agent?
(SIGHS) No, sir.
My-- My pickup broke down
out on the road.
Or just some kind of pervert?
(SIGHS) I just was gonna ask
for some help with my engine.
Hiram, he was creeping
around the woods.
In the woods?
-Son, were you gonna ask a bear?
-(CHUCKLES)
-No, sir.
-What's that?
That was funny.
(CHUCKLES)
It was kind of funny, wasn't it?
Son, were you gonna
ask a bear? (LAUGHS)
Hey, who says I can't be funny?
Huh?
-Not me, sir.
-Me neither.
Nor I.
(SHOUTS) Son,
were you gonna ask a bear?
(MEN LAUGHING)
Everyone, listen. Listen.
Son, were you gonna ask a bear?
(CHUCKLES)
Ask a bear.
What the fuck is he doing here?
Dad, this son of a bitch just
tried robbing me at gunpoint.
(LEFTY MOANING) Oh.
(COUGHS)
My daughter and I
may have our differences,
but I will not
tolerate anyone...
(COCKS HAMMER)
...threatening
the sanctity of her life.
(OBJECT THUDS)
(MELANCHOLY MUSIC PLAYING)
-(HIRAM MOANS)
-(WOMEN GASP)
(MANDY) Oh, fuck!
(GUNSHOT)
-(ARROW LANDS)
-(GRUNTING)
-(MAN) Shit.
-(MANDY) Fuck!
-(MAN) Look out.
-What the fuck?
-(ABBY SHRIEKS)
-(MANDY) Get inside!
Sir, we got you.
Come on.
You're gonna be all right.
Bar the doors!
Don't let anyone in.
(PLATES CLATTERING)
(MANDY)
They're fucking everywhere!
-(WOMEN CRYING)
-(MAN) Shut up.
(GASPING)
-(MOM) Hiram! Hiram!
-(MAN) Get up!
Hiram! Hiram!
What do they want?
They must want our women.
No, man.
They want the fucking shirt!
-What shirt?
-(MOM) They keep shooting at us.
The fucking...
I stole this old Indian shirt,
and I came here for protection,
and they must have found out.
(MOM YELPS)
So are we gonna get
these guns out or what?
We need everybody armed.
Show of force.
Okay, that's the only way
we're gonna scare them away.
Excuse me. Arm the women?
I don't think so.
-Hiram?
-(ARROW LANDS)
-(HANK) Open up!
-(BANGING ON DOOR)
Open the goddamn door.
(GROANING, GRUNTING)
(GHOST EYE)
Keep up the attack.
Don't stand down.
(GASPING)
(MOM) Hiram!
-(ARROWS THUDDING)
-(GASPING)
-(GASPS)
-Hiram, what are we gonna do?
We're gonna get
the goddamn guns out
so that we don't get
fucking killed.
Okay? Mom, listen. Look at me.
Tell them it was all my fault.
My fault, okay? Okay?
Okay.
Mom, the keys. I need the keys
to get to the guns.
-Okay.
-(HIRAM MOANS) Grace.
-Grace. No.
-(MAN) There's more of 'em.
Mom, give me the keys please!
(MAN) Don't you do it!
(GIRL)
They're still shooting at us!
-(GRACE GROANS)
-Fuck yeah.
(MANDY) Sh--
(MAN)
What's going on over there?
I don't think so, sweetheart.
Not on my watch.
(GUNSHOT)
-(GASPS)
-(BLOOD SPATTERS)
(ARROW LANDS)
-Go. Go.
-Hurry!
-(ARROW THUDS)
-(ABBY) Amanda, go faster.
Hey, hey, hey.
What do you think you're doing?
(MANDY) Which fucking key is it?
Hiram forbids it.
Oh, fuck off!
(PAINED GRUNTS)
-(MANDY) Mom, shoot him.
-(BARREL SPINS)
(HAMMER CLICKS)
-(GRACE) It won't shoot.
-(GROWLS) Fuck off!
(METAL SCRAPES)
-(THUD)
-(SHOUTS)
-Abby!
-(MANDY) Hey, asshole.
(GUNSHOT)
I just cleaned this floor.
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
(MAN) What's going on?
Whoa, look!
-I'm not even armed.
-Hey, open up.
Okay, I'm just
that son of a bitch's stepson.
I didn't want to come
to this fucked-up
Little House on the Prairie,
whatever this is.
(MAN) Open the goddamn door.
-(GRACE) Oh, God!
-(GIRL) Don't let him out!
(GRACE SCREAMS)
What in the sam hell?
(GROANS)
(GRACE) Good girl.
Jesus,
they're shooting each other.
(PANTING)
Calliope?
Amanda?
Let's all get outta here
this time.
Okay?
(SHERIFF GROANING)
No. No, please. Please.
(GUN FIRES TWICE)
(GHOST EYE) Hold your fire!
Name's Henry Alvin Jordan.
But I answer to Ghost Eye.
Born and raised in
prisoner of war camp number 334.
I'm the leader
of the Red Thunder Society.
It's a people's army devoted
to maintaining our traditions
and the restoration
of our proper domain.
A people's what?
A people's army.
-A what?
-Jesus, lady.
You know the American Indian
Movement, The Black Panthers?
(MANDY) No.
Well, we're like that.
Freedom fighters,
guerrilla warriors,
not to be fucked with.
Who are you?
My name is Amanda Bethany Starr.
But I answer to Mandy.
And, uh, right now,
I'm apparently
in the middle
of a goddamn murder spree,
so I'm not
to be fucked with either.
What do you want?
The ghost shirt.
(MANDY) So what is it?
It's ours.
It's a symbol of our history
and our independence.
It was stolen from our tribe.
Yeah, well I guess
we've all got our problems.
Besides, that thing's supposed
to be worth a lot of money.
I'm not just gonna hand it over.
Then you wanna work out
some kind of deal?
We can try.
You said it. Hank.
-We got your little brother.
-(GIRL) What brother?
I don't have a little brother.
He's my son, Cal,
and he has absolutely nothing
to do with this.
You try telling him that.
He says he's the reincarnation
of Sitting Bull.
In fact, he promised to lead us,
his people, to the ghost shirt.
You know,
I was pretty skeptical myself,
but I gotta say... (CHUCKLES)
so far, so good.
Look, man, there's a guy
on his way here right now
who wants to buy
your precious ghost shirt. Okay?
His name is Roy Lee Dean.
You take care of him,
and I'll fucking
give you the shirt. Okay?
But me and my family
keep the bastard's money.
Win-win and we all get
the fuck out of Dodge.
All right.
You got yourself a deal.
Good.
Now send in the boy
and we'll all wait patiently
for Mr. Fuckface to arrive.
No way.
We're holding on to the kid.
You try to cross us,
he's a goner.
-You got that?
-Yeah, I got that.
But if you so much as
put a scratch on my son's arm,
I'll stab you
in the fucking heart.
You got that?
Yeah. I catch the general drift.
A son? Who's the father?
I don't know, Mom.
Do you remember the name
of every single asshole
who paid Dad off to spend
an hour behind that door?
So...
-how have things been here?
-(GIRL CHUCKLES)
-Better now.
-(GRACE LAUGHS)
(WOMEN CHUCKLE)
("STREETS OF LAREDO"
BY EDDY ARNOLD PLAYS)
♪ As I walked out
In the streets of Laredo ♪
In Laredo one day ♪
♪ I spied a poor cowboy
Wrapped up in white linen ♪
♪ Wrapped up in white linen
As cold as the clay ♪
♪ I see by your outfit
That you are a cowboy ♪
(EXHALES)
(GRUNTING)
♪ These words he did say
As I boldly stepped by ♪
♪ Come sit down beside me ♪
♪ And hear my sad story ♪
(GHOST EYE)
Hey, cowboy's alive.
♪ I was shot in the breast ♪
♪ And I know I must die ♪
♪ Oh beat the drum slowly ♪
Hmm? Mm. Mm.
(GHOST EYE)
Shh. Someone's coming.
♪ And play the fife lowly ♪
(ENGINE PURRS)
♪ Play the Death March
As you carry me along ♪
Huh.
(SIGHS)
♪ Take me to the valley there
Lay the sod o'er me ♪
(LINE RINGS)
You gotta be fucking kidding me.
-(LINE TRILLING)
-Pick up.
-(PHONE VIBRATES)
-(LINE BEEPS)
Shit.
(EXHALES)
I hope they spell my name right
in the papers.
Uh-uh.
(UPBEAT BANJO STRUMMING)
(CAR APPROACHES SLOWLY)
(LEFTY GROANING)
(DOOR OPENS)
All right, I'm here.
Let's try and make this
quick and easy, okay?
(MANDY) You alone?
Indeed I am. How about you?
Fuck yeah. Of course.
What's with these poor dead
hombres on your front porch?
Little bit of family drama.
You got that money?
I got 50 grand right here
and the other 50's in the trunk
when we make the exchange.
You got that ghost shirt?
Yeah. Bring me all the cash
and I'll show you
right where it is.
I don't know. That's got me
assuming a lot of risk.
Let's not overthink
a happy situation.
(GRUNTING)
Oh, and one of these
poor dead hombres?
He ain't that dead.
Yeah, well, he should be.
(DEAN) How about this?
As a gesture of goodwill,
I'll take care of
this crawling corpse for you.
Just bring me
that pretty little Indian shirt,
you'll be $100,000 richer.
Yeah, and how the fuck do I know
you won't shoot me too?
Lady, take a look at my car.
Come look at these
custom-made snakeskin boots
and this vintage
19th-century belt buckle,
gifted to me
by Mr. Wilford Brimley himself.
Okay, so?
So, I'm the region's
most respected dealer
in high-end Western artifacts
and the goddamn walking,
talking embodiment
of the cowboy code.
Meaning... my word is my bond.
Just as a FYI,
this dead body here's
still crawling away.
Okay, then shoot
the fucking bastard!
Yeah? Happy to.
(GHOST EYE WHISPERS)
Okay. Go, go.
(WHIMPERS)
(CALVIN MURMURS)
Doing you a favor, man.
-(CALVIN) Mm-mm!
-(GUNSHOT)
-Mm!
-(GUNSHOT ECHOES)
(CHUCKLES) Amazing.
(SIGHS)
Reggie Dale.
Very slowly and very carefully
look outside.
Whoa.
(RIFLES CLATTER)
(DEAN) Steady now.
Remember, this is just simply
a business transaction.
There's no need
to get emotional.
Everyone just stay calm.
How about you leave
all the cash on the ground,
get back in the car, and
then calmly drive the fuck away.
That wasn't our deal!
Yeah, neither
was an armed gunman
hiding in your fucking trunk.
Fuck.
All right, look...
I'm willing to
go up to 150 grand,
and you all split it up
however you like.
Not everything's for sale,
you capitalist fuck.
(MANDY)
You're outnumbered, man.
Leave the money and
drive away while you still can.
We gotta take out
at least one side.
Broads or the Indians?
It's Native Americans,
Reggie Dale,
and stop distracting me.
I'm trying to negotiate.
Oh, yeah? With exactly
what leverage, Mr. Businessman?
Oh.
I can't believe it.
Dipshit's actually right.
-(GUNSHOT)
-(GROANS)
(REGGIE DALE)
Yeah!
Fuck yeah, Uncle Roy Lee.
-(AUTOMATIC GUNFIRE)
-(LEFTY GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS, GASPS)
Mmm!
(ABBY) What's she doing?
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
(STOPS)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS) Oh.
(HANK) She gave us away.
Cal, where are you?
-Cal!
-Mmm.
-(GRUNTS)
-(GUNFIRE)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS SOFTLY)
(QUIETLY) Fuck.
-(EXHALES)
-Hmm?
(PANTING)
I'm the reincarnation
of Sitting Bull,
the great Lakota war chief.
Mmm. (MUFFLED SPEECH)
I've returned.
(STAMMERING) It's a--
It's an honor to... meet you.
Do you need... help
bringing the... ghost shirt...
back to your... people?
Yes, please.
Okay.
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
That's her?
(EXHALES)
(DEAN) Whoever you are,
I know you're still out there.
Unless you're too chickenshit
to stand your ground,
let's have it out right now.
Fuck.
-(BOW TWANGS)
-(ARROW WHIZZES)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
-(GUNSHOT)
-(GRUNTS)
Aw. (CHUCKLES)
No wonder we won.
(GROANS SOFTLY)
Fucking waitress is here?
Big gun-down, huh?
Fuck you.
(ENGINE REVS)
(ENGINE STOPS)
(MANDY) Cal!
I know I fucked everything up,
but I'm still your mother, okay?
I can be.
I wanna be. I really do.
(SNIFFS) My mother died
many, many years ago.
(CRIES)
Yeah. I guess she did.
Get him out of here, please.
Get him somewhere safe.
(SOBS)
Come on.
(GROANS)
(PENNY JO)
I'll be right... back.
Who are-- Who are you?
The reincarnation
of Sitting Bull.
Who are you?
Lefty Ledbetter.
But I'm actually right-handed.
Thank you.
(DEAN GROANS)
(STAMMERING) Let's... go.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(GROANS)
(CRIES) No!
-(GRACE) It's okay.
-(GRUNTS)
We got you.
(GRUNTS)
Fuck.
(GASPING, GRUNTING)
(INHALES)
(LAUGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
-Wild West, ba--
-(ARROW THUDS)
(ENGINE RUMBLES, STOPS)
Are you... sure about this?
I've returned the ghost shirt
back to my people.
They'll recognize who I am now.
Don't be sad.
I'm home.
(SOFT ACOUSTIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(LEFTY COUGHS)
(SPUTTERS, COUGHS)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(COUGHING)
Stop! (GASPS)
(MAN ON THE RADIO) You're
listening to the classic sounds
of the west here
on South Dakota--
(EXHALES)
(STAMMERING)
You... need a doctor.
No. I don't.
(GRUNTS)
You don't... look too good.
(EXHALES)
I know I...
don't have a very exciting life.
I know I'm not too exciting
either.
I don't drive a fancy car.
I don't have a fancy job.
I'm not a part
of anybody's country club.
But I do have a nice house.
A strong back.
And a heart full
of love to give.
The world is so full of bad--
so full of bad things.
It's frightening.
Especially if you're alone.
(GASPS)
People shouldn't be alone.
People...
People... should be happy.
I think I can make you happy.
That's why I want you
to be my happy wife.
For me to be your happy husband.
Penny... Penny Jo...
Poplin. Penny... Jo... Poplin.
Penny Jo... Pop...
(EXHALES)
Lefty?
Lef-- Lefty?
("ONE MORE NIGHT"
BY IAN NOE PLAYS)
(CRYING)
♪ There were no people left ♪
♪ When the ship rolled in ♪
♪ No one around to explain ♪
♪ All the years
They had traveled ♪
♪ In search of kin ♪
♪ Now seemed
A journey in vain ♪
♪ One more night coming down
They cry ♪
♪ One more night
Through this hometown blur ♪
'Neath this ancient sky ♪
♪ Take the time to recall
Who we were ♪
(SIGHS)
♪ Well, they headed over
Vermont ♪
♪ Like spaced-out tramps ♪
(SOBBING, CHUCKLES)
♪ Years of destruction
They saw ♪
♪ With their eyes growing heavy
They set up camp ♪
Hi.
♪ Outside an old Florida mall ♪
♪ One more night coming down
They cry ♪
(QUIET SOBS)
♪ One more night
In this hometown blur ♪
'Neath this ancient sky ♪
♪ Take the time to recall
Who we were ♪
(RELIEVED CHUCKLES)
My baby boy.
(WITHOUT STAMMERING)
♪ It's been
A long, dark night ♪
♪ And I've been waiting
For morning ♪
♪ It's been
A long, hard fight ♪
♪ But I see a brand new day
Dawning ♪
♪ I've been looking
For sunshine ♪
♪ You know I ain't seen it
In so long ♪
♪ Everything's gonna
Work out just fine ♪
♪ Everything's gonna be
All right ♪
♪ That's been all wrong ♪
(INHALES)
("HOMBRE" BY DAN REEDER PLAYING)
♪ Well, a bad-looking hombre
Rode up on me ♪
♪ On the back
Of a cold, black mare ♪
♪ He squinted and spat
Adjusted his hat ♪
♪ Said, we don't need your kind
Around here ♪
♪ When I pulled back my cape
He saw a pistol ♪
♪ When the smoke cleared
He lay dead in the sand ♪
♪ Pity the cowboy
Who draws on me ♪
♪ I was born
With a six-gun in my hand ♪
♪ Well, that cowboy
He ain't alone ♪
♪ There's plenty more
Like him around ♪
♪ Buried in the boothills
Of this wide land ♪
♪ By the man born
With a six-gun in his hand ♪
♪ If you find yourself
Up in the northwest ♪
♪ Between
Bismarck, Butte and Cheyenne ♪
♪ Remember the story
About the bad-lookin' hombre ♪
♪ And the man born
With a six-gun in his hand ♪
(MELANCHOLY MUSIC PLAYING)
(UPBEAT COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING)